Dioris Diaz

diorisd@gmail.com | 267-320-7168 | Philadelphia, PA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dioris-diaz-18a053191/ | Github: https://github.com/Dioris-cpu |

Portfolio: http://diorisdiaz.com/

A Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in operations and retail management for warehouse industries. Experienced in building market driven applications using languages and frameworks in JavaScript, CSS, Node.js, Express.js,MongoDB, and React.js. Noted as being a collaborative problem solver who is focused on developing responsive applications that help find better solutions to everyday problems. Excited to implement new ideas, strategies and collaborate with fellow developers and employers to a mission driven company.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Languages:</u> Express.js, React.js, Node.js, JavaScript ES5/ES6, Shopify, Polaris, GraphQl, Apollo, Handlebars.js, JQuery, JSON, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Heroku, REST APIs, Twitter Bootstrap, Sequelize, Google Materialize

<u>Databases</u>: MongoDB, MySQL

Miscellaneous: Mac, Git/Github, Google Suite, IOS

APPLICATIONS BUILT

TripTips | Back End Web Developer | Visit Site View Code

- A travel itinerary creator, displays and shares travel plans with users all across the country.
- Responsible for establishing routes for the back end of the application and utilized SQL to store new users/itineraries.
- Built back end in Node.Js, enabled Nodemailer to send itineraries to users emails.

WishDish | Front End Web Developer | Visit Site View Code

- An efficient restaurant search application that displays the top restaurants based on the users geolocation and cuisine of choice .
- Collaborated with other developers in implementing the design of application to attract users
- Built front end in Javascript, queried data from multiple APIs in order to ensure the functionality of nearby restaurants around users designated location.

Quaranitni | Full Stack Web Developer | Visit Site View Code

- Quarantini is an app that helps users make delicious cocktails when trapped at home.
- Built back end in MongoDB Atlas, functionality that allows users to create their own cocktails, as well as share their recipes with others users.

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant **TechGirlz**, Remote

2020 - Current

Operations Manager, GoPuff, Philadelphia, PA

7/2018 - Current

• Manage over 50+ associates by training, assigning tasks, coordinating schedules across warehouse and other departments.

Freelance; Full-Stack Web Developer. Noside (Musician), Philadelphia, PA

6/2020 - Current

- Noside Shopify App | Visit Site View Code
- Responsible for designing and maintaining development of websites for Noside (Musician) in order to promote his music and talents to the music industry.
- Utilized technologies such as Shopify, and React to build the front and back end of application

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

- Certificate - Javascript Full Stack Web Development Program